This is Wyatt from Castle Island.
A few weeks ago, I teamed up with Jake Lynch and Henry Harris from our team
to publish an article that explored how to best value a DeFi protocol.
In particular, what key metrics should be used to assess value,
starting with DeFi lending markets, as these are a cornerstone application of the ecosystem.
In retrospect, the September and early October period that we spent doing research
leading up to publishing the report marked a cyclical high in the industry.
Since then, and namely after the October 10th crash,
crypto token valuations have cratered and DeFi metrics are down markedly across the board.
In this episode, Jake and I sit down to discuss some of the topics from our report
and their relevance to the current environment.
Above all else, where does this major sell-off leave us,
what is still lasting and important in DeFi, and where do we go from here?
Without further ado, I hope you enjoy our conversation.
Matt Walsh and Nick Carter are partners at Castle Island Ventures.
All of these expressed by them or the guests on this podcast are solely their opinions
and do not reflect the opinions of Castle Island Ventures.
Guests and hosts may maintain positions in the assets discussed in this podcast.
You should not treat any opinion expressed by anyone on this podcast
as a specific inducement to make a particular investment or follow a particular strategy,
but only as an expression of their personal opinion.
This podcast is for informational purposes only.
This is a different kind of market and the Fed is asleep.
The federal government is stepping it to stabilize Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac,
the two mortgage giants that have been threatened by the housing crisis.
The bank of England has pumped 75 billion pounds more to Britain's ailing economy
with a new round of quantitative easing.
You print a couple trillion dollars and all of a sudden people start to worry.
So out of this worry, we have something called the Bitcoin. Bitcoin.
Jake, thanks for sitting down.
The topic of our conversation today, so you, Henry and I, a few weeks ago,
published a report that we've been working on for some time.
I think it was a question that we'd all grappled with over the last year plus
where we were trying to get a sense of what matters when you're valuing DeFi protocols, DeFi apps.
People talk about TVL a lot, total value locked,
which I think you've seen businesses like Turtle Club and Royco,
which are explicitly capital raising tools for DeFi protocols and apps.
You've seen the success of them.
I think a lot of people question how important that actually is
and whether it's worthwhile and actually added up to the core value of these things.
It's funny because in a few ways it does remind me of the conversations people were having
in the early internet era when they were saying,
is users the important metric of a marketplace or of a social application
or is it total process volume or is it number of website visits
or is it number of different offerings or skews.
So I don't think it's uncommon to have this conversation about
what actually matters in these emerging business types.
But it comes at a funny time because we put this out in late October.
The lending markets were the topic of focus
and since then the total value locked in these lending markets has shuttered.
You look at the chart and it's a pretty direct downward inflection.
Altcoin markets have been severely challenged, especially since then.
So I have my views which we'll dive into, but where do you think that leaves us overall?
It's a good point.
The lending markets to me are specifically interesting in crypto
because they are one of the most sustainable businesses
and I think what you're pointing out is that there is still a lot of noise there.
Why are they sustainable in your view?
We can zoom out a little bit and talk about the business models in crypto in general.
Broadly speaking, most crypto falls into DeFi
and the DeFi stack splits into what I would consider two major categories.
One has to do with crypto's use for tokenization
so that settlement, that swapping, those are these activities
that are instantaneous one-time use activities
and then the other is capital formation.
So this has really been the year of capital formation.
You see this with the rapid iteration of launch pads that we've seen
but you also see this in lending.
And the tokenization side, the swapping and the settlement, very cyclical business.
This business is almost like there's a summer aspect to DeFi summer.
That's why we call it that.
With capital formation, this is like an evergreen business.
This is one thing that crypto directly serves the value prop of
and you really can't do this capital formation outside of crypto.
And what are you describing in this context as capital formation?
There's two forms.
I mean, today we're going to talk about the lending form.
The other form is raising capital.
And I think that's what's going on with MetaDow,
what went on with Pumpfun, all of that was super interesting
and it's a great business.
But the lending markets have this really, really sticky user base
and this user base is fundamentally just seeking yield on their assets.
They're trying to turn nonproductive assets into productive assets.
And this is similar to stablecoin volume.
This doesn't go away with the season.
This is constantly something people are seeking to do.
So that's one of the reasons I think lending is one of the more durable businesses in crypto.
And we can dive all into the different types of lending,
but that's what makes it interesting.
With the TVL drop off, I think this cuts into a recent trend that we've seen,
which is the forms of lending and borrowing to use cases that we see on chain
have completely changed over the past year to two years.
So originally, if you look at what lending started as,
it started as CDPs where you would put up money
and you would get a synthetic dollar essentially against this.
I'm going to roll you back for a second.
I actually don't think you can talk even about how well the defile lending platforms
like Ave and Morfo have done without talking about the void that was left by Celsius and BlockFi
that had built what's probably the most straightforward use case of crypto,
which is I want to own Bitcoin and as much more Bitcoin as I can and less dollars,
but have spendable dollars against that Bitcoin.
I think it's that cut and simple.
And I think a big part of the success of those platforms was the fact that
Celsius and BlockFi and others not only went away,
but bred mistrust in those platforms and the defile platforms benefited from that.
Yeah, and I think we can talk a lot about trust.
There's still a degree of trust me that goes into the platforms today.
And that's one of the things that we went into in this piece is rapidly these on chain platforms.
They're auditable.
You can see what's going on there,
but you almost need a PhD today to actually understand the risk that you're getting paid for.
And this is fundamental to the lending markets is it's not risk-free.
It's as close to the risk-free rate as you can get.
So you go back to Celsius and you have this huge need to unlock capital
that's just sitting there in these long positions that people want to use.
They want to unlock and for whatever reason,
whether it's taxes or whether it's just fundamentally that they want to hold on to it.
Ideologically, they go to a lender to try to unlock the capital.
This use case is still pretty persistent.
And this is probably one of the most durable trades that we see on lending markets today.
I mean, it has to be.
It's extremely durable.
So like a great example of this is the Morpho integration with Coinbase.
So Morpho is integrated with Coinbase so you can borrow against your CBBTC,
which is Coinbase's RAP Bitcoin.
And this has just been growing exponentially since they started earlier this year.
It's over one and a half billion dollars of collateral in Bitcoin.
And this use case, when you look at the TVL chart in the drop-off after October,
this has not been hindered at all.
What you do see in the drop-off after October is another strategy that we saw come out recently,
which is this idea of looping.
For those who haven't listened to Henry and Corinne's podcast about the vaults,
this is extremely relevant for this.
But the general idea of looping is I have some yield-bearing token.
The yield might be coming from any of many sources.
Treasury yield, right-staking yield, basis trade through USDA, RWA lending, any of these.
And the idea or the realization that lending markets had is they can lend to these at a pretty high LTV.
And when you lend to them at a really high LTV, you can actually recycle that capital.
So you put in asset, you borrow against the stablecoin, you buy asset,
you put asset back in and you borrow against it.
And you continue to do this.
And what you can do is you can take a yield from maybe 10% on an unlevered basis
and lever it up to call it 25, 30%.
So this is what we really saw leading into October when we released this piece.
And admittedly, this was very scary.
And the reason this was very scary was because it's really two reasons.
One is, although crypto is extremely traceable, it's virtually impossible to identify how levered a system is.
It's very possible to go and do this looping on multiple platforms or from multiple accounts.
So this is not something that's easily traceable, not just to us,
but we spoke to all of the major lending protocols and all of them agreed that they don't know themselves.
It's not something that they can measure.
The second thing that's scary about this is the underlying increasingly went down the risk curve.
And what I mean by this is USDA is a relatively vanilla strategy.
Ever since I've been at L1D, we've been getting pitched basis trade funds.
And this was super popular in 2021.
When USDA came out, it just evaporated the basis trade fund pitch.
We stopped seeing them entirely.
And the reason being is because USDA essentially commodified that trade
and they wrapped it in a token and they made it so anybody can really access it with way less friction and they handle the infrastructure.
Now, this is something that a lot of crypto people are familiar with the risks on.
So they're comfortable underwriting it.
So when you see USDA being 20% of the Aave lending pool, you don't want the concentration risk perhaps,
but you're okay with the underlying risk.
What we saw after this is this implementation of this strategy across different vault strategies.
And by vault strategies, I really mean this idea of putting your tokens into a vault
and them running some sort of trading strategy beneath it.
There are levels of obfuscation that people use.
So going into the elixir event, what we discovered is essentially these vaults were just cross depositing into themselves.
And this is extremely dangerous because essentially you take one fund
and you're spreading the same amount of risk across all the other funds.
So this was a strategy that I think we really rightfully identified as not extremely durable.
It was very profitable for a lot of lending protocols.
It will continue to be a strategy that lending protocols enable,
but this is not what I would consider to be the bet on lending markets, so to speak.
I fully agree and you left me with a few different points.
I first off want to replay why we're having this conversation
and then some of the key points you brought up, which were you and I as long-term investors
in the business of finding what the good and lasting business models are
and we're looking at lending in crypto as one case of those
because what we think is a market gap that'll grow
and because of what we think could be strengths of why that business model is durable, which you made points on.
And then in examining those lending protocols,
trying to pick out what's important and vetting the risks to your point
and that you see these metrics like total value locked inflecting up,
but you don't know the sense of how much leverage is in the system.
And what I've thought is a very funny characteristic of the current crypto market
where so long composability or all the apps working well together
was such a North Star that people wanted.
And lo and behold, as a result of that, you get very composable risk,
which means that one of these yield-bearing stablecoins becomes insolvent
and it's a big problem for the lending protocol.
It's a big problem for ever curating that lending pool.
It's a big problem for assets that are in a vault with those assets.
It's a problem for everything else around.
I want to touch on those points specifically, but I did want to replay.
That's our core exploration here.
And I wanted to ask you on the record,
do you think that 1010 happened because of this leverage profile that we're talking about?
1010 being the major crypto washout that happened a few weeks back.
That's a really good question.
I hope you share your thoughts after.
So if you look at 1010,
I think that this risk played a major role in how conservative
the perpetual exchanges were with their own risk.
And what I mean by that specifically is leading into 1010,
you had call it $6 to $8 billion of USD in Aave.
And Aave is by any definition,
probably the most systemically important protocol in crypto.
And this amount of USD being essentially pushed into the big risk house in crypto
made it so that any tremors in this asset would have huge, huge, huge downstream effects.
So Aave went as far as to peg USD to USDT.
This is an extreme measure.
I wouldn't recommend hard pegging any asset in a lending market,
but this turned out to be extremely necessary in this case
because what ended up as far as we can tell causing 1010
was a poor liquidation of USD on Binance
in order in the amount of maybe $60 million that was dumped on an order book
that was not $60 million deep.
And Binance's oracle being tied into USD order book on its own platform.
So the question as to what caused 1010,
I think the direct answer is probably this bad liquidation.
But the indirect answer, it could definitely be ascribed to the fear that was around USD,
the fear that was around this heavily levered asset.
What do you think?
I think that a lot of that is true.
I think the liquidation piece spurred it in the moment, if that makes sense.
I'm going to be pretty harsh on a lot of the assets in the industry at this moment,
which is to say that I think the degree of pain felt was because of how thin
a lot of the order book depth is on a lot of these assets and across a lot of venues.
With the outcome being that you have an asset that let's say it trades at a $200 million market cap
and supposedly it has $5 million a daily volume,
but the order book depth within reason is a couple percent.
So realistically, you can only trade a couple hundred thousand something like that of an asset like this
without materially moving the market, probably less actually, but let's call it that.
The outcome of that is that if you do have an initial liquidation of size
or you have a market tremor that distresses a sizable market actor
and they need to start liquidating or selling assets across a set of assets in the ecosystem,
because those order books are not very deep, the price of these assets are going to fall really fast.
To the point where someone could easily argue,
a lot of these assets probably aren't worth what their claimed market cap is
in the sense that yes, the price of the asset as it trades on exchanges
times the number of tokens in circulation is that $200 million market cap,
but you can only functionally trade $250,000 of the asset per day
and if not, the market moves 10, 20 percent.
I think we have a lot of assets like that in our ecosystem.
This is fundamentally the fear and the cloud that's over everybody's head right now
is when you look at all of the charts today, you have to zoom out
because we now have this 95 percent candle on 10 fat
and you're reminded that the fundamental floor is not necessarily there for a lot of assets,
but the thing that I think you want to hone in on
and the real question for people in crypto is are any of these assets worth anything?
Definitely and one question I was going to ask you from your seat
because you guys invest in funds as well.
How do you think about investing in funds that are going to invest in these long tail of crypto tokens
that are going to mark them or report what they're worth to you guys
and let's say they own $10 million of a token that trades at $200 million of the fictional token that I mentioned.
They can't recognize that value.
How do you think about having this portfolio of managers and tokens of value that to your point
is difficult to liquidate, doesn't have a fundamental floor?
How do you navigate that?
This is a question we deal with every day and honestly this is a really strong case
for why a fund of funds makes sense in crypto
is because we see many funds that will mark a position
that we see to be a position maybe its FDV is $500 million
and it has $25,000 of volume per day
and they'll mark this at the value of $500 million.
With our managers we have very strict essentially valuation policies built in
so for extremely illiquid assets we're talking about assets that just came into existence
that might have a 10% float or something like this
you have to put a massive discount on these assets
and the reason we have to do that is not because we think that it's necessarily the right thing to do
it's because we're economically incentivized as allocators to make sure that we're not overpaying in fees
If you take a malicious example here
a fund could easily inflate their nav and charge you the fees on that performance
Does that happen?
Of course it happens.
How do those conversations go?
I think this is something people in industry probably don't know a ton about
So generally there's two types of funds
Ray from L&D speaks about this all the time
there's the GBB and GPA
you can in not so many words categorize them as whether they want management fees or performance fees
the number one thing you can do to avoid having to deal with this issue in the first place
is go for people who are looking for performance fees
because any good fund out there knows that if they overinflate their book
on an asset that's not really worth that much
and it draws down that their high watermark is too high for them to get over
and explain why that's a problem because it's an important point
a problem for us or a problem for them?
Problem for them? Felipe talked about this when he was on
The general concept of the high watermark I think isn't really well known to a lot of non-LPs
but essentially if you bring your nav up to 100 and then it drops back down
and then it goes up partially to 100
you're not making performance fees on this until you breach what your high watermark was
call it that 100 mark
unless you bring in that new capital or whatever
So in this circumstance
if you're a manager and you want to incentivize really good talent
you're not going to be able to pay that talent
So it is trivially easy in crypto to go into a token
have it launch, have it go up 10x
but be completely locked for like a year
and then you go to your fund admin and you say it's worth whatever that 10x value is
and all of a sudden your investors have to pay fees on that unrealized
essentially on what that is
As a liquid fund to be clear
Yeah, as a liquid fund
As a venture fund that's not an issue
you get paid on the way out
As a liquid fund the fees are crystallized annually essentially
If you draw down below that high watermark
all of your talent is going to leave
because they're going to recognize that they're not going to have the big payday that they want it
So it's in your favor to market conservatively
and once that asset gets to a mature level
where you can actually liquidate it safely
that's when you get paid
So this is what smart managers is what the good managers do
malicious managers or negligent managers
will allow this to happen to their fund
and one of two things will happen
either their team leaves or their investors leave
With that in mind
that you have these assets that trade at these multiples
do you think it's just a reality that as we get better market discovery
a lot of these assets will trade down to lower prices
just because they're finding an actual value once you take away an illiquidity premium
No, I don't think so
and the reason I don't think so is because
there are many ways to construct a value
when you look at TradFi it's not like you see extremely rational valuations either
So why do things trade where they do?
There are many reasons
depending on what the asset is
there would be different things that go into the valuation
to tie it back to the lending markets for example
one of the reasons we did this piece in the first place
is because you see that a lot of these lending protocols are valued
seemingly on a ratio to their TVL
and this does not mean that the markets are rational
this just means that the market is probably valuing it on the wrong thing
it actually indicates that the market is rational
yeah, there are groupings
so you have Aave trading relative to Morpho based on TVL
but when you dig into what the business of Aave or Morpho really is
it's a business of loans
it's not a business of how many dollars you can put in a smart contract
it's a business of how many dollars you take out of a smart contract
and this is where the market needs to step up
and I think where the market can really mature
Theo would tell you all about how they approach valuation for protocols like this
but fundamentally it comes down to figuring out
what is a revenue driving activity
what is a meaningful activity in the protocol
and valuing it based on that
another really good example of this is
if you go back to 2021, 2022, 2023
nobody really understood L1s
they still don't
so the way that they would compare L1s was on two things
and I'm not innocent of this
but you would look at user metrics
and you would look at GitHub commits
and anybody today if you told that to
will rightfully tell you that
okay, user metrics is probably the worst metric in the world
because as soon as you start looking at it
everybody can fake it
and then GitHub commits is not a great metric
because different companies are at different stages of developing that
so there's a cyclicality to GitHub commits
where if you're going to be pushing FireDancer this month
you're going to have a ton of commits
and there are ways to just hammer GitHub commits with no value
there are programs out there
that will allow you to code
how you want your GitHub commits to look
so you can write things on your GitHub
in the ice green squares
so yeah, these are extremely gameable metrics
but what's not a gameable metric is revenue paying metrics
at the very end of the day
somebody is paying that revenue
this reminds me a bit
and I remember when we talked about this
in this study of how in traditional finance
you'll just have stock prices swing
during periods where there's discovery
of what bucket even a mature company
should trade in from a multiple perspective
where people will be like
oh, it's not a SaaS business, it's a consulting business
so therefore it shouldn't trade at 15 actions to trade at 5
and it'll bump down 60% of years
those things really happen
and we're seeing that kind of discovery in our industry
a great example of this is
a bank out there who put a report out on figure
figure went public
they're starting to get coverage by real banks
and you scroll down to the comps
and in the comps section
you have a list of companies
including Coinbase and Circle
and the only thing that Coinbase, Circle and Figure have in common
is Figure has a early stage exchange
which is not a big component to its revenue
and they're in crypto
but it's very much so in that phase that you're describing
where you're trying to say
okay, so what PE ratio should we assign to this?
what sector is this in?
at this point in crypto
we have a really good viewpoint on what the sectors are in crypto
I've tried this sector mapping exercise almost every year
and it wasn't until the past two years
where it became consensus with what everybody sees
which is what? Lending, trading
so on the DeFi stack you start with issuance
so issuance can take two forms
either you're issuing an asset that exists
like an RWA issuance platform
Circle is a great example
or you're issuing a new asset
which would be a launchpad
MetaDow, Pump, Echo, all of these
after you do issuance you have settlement
settlement very much so is L1s
you settle your assets on a blockchain
after settlement is swapping
if you don't have swapping
you can't do anything else interesting at all in crypto
so swapping is one asset for another
everybody knows the swapping protocols
once you have swapping
you can liquidate assets
and so you allow for lending
and then after lending
becomes a new category
that I like to call strategies
so this is this vault category
this is like Lido as well
this is this category where it's
I want to take an asset that is a non-productive asset
turn into a productive asset
and then lastly and I would put this
adjacent to all of these
is this category that I would call
probably asset management or custody
and this is where we see
you might have squads and knows the safe
you might also have copper and firebox
you have a lot of C5 DeFi overlaps here
so broadly speaking
this is every single thing
that you're going to do in crypto
fits within these categories
and you can have different flavors of this
you can have gaming
but in gaming
you will introduce these DeFi elements
whether it's settlement
whether it swaps
whether it's lending
in NFTs
you do the same thing
in DePin
you have
I'll be honest
primarily just issuance
but it's very likely that we'll get a step
beyond this like with USDAI
where you have issuance going into lending
going into strategies
going into those things
so I think that sector map
lays out pretty clearly there
now that we have this sector map
it's the crypto community's job
to start to underwrite these things
more intelligently
so this is where you ask
for more interesting metrics
so one of the things that we pointed out
in this piece
is you couldn't write this piece
without pointing out
what you think is the better metric for lending
and I think it was pretty obvious to us
that the most important metric
in lending
is really the availability of stablecoins
on that platform
whether it's USDC
whether it's USDT
these stablecoins
are overwhelmingly what is being borrowed
so in order for a loan to exist
you need an asset that they're going to borrow against
and very few people want to borrow WBTC
because they're effectively going short Bitcoin
everybody in the world wants to lend WBTC
you see this
there's ten billion dollars
of WBTC sitting on Ave
with nobody borrowing it
and the reason being is because
that eight basis points of borrow
yield is the best that they're going to get out there
what I want to see in the lending protocols going forward
is essentially evaluation that is more hinged on
how good are these teams at finding dollars
to capital raising
exactly
getting their dollars on platform
so that they can be utilized
and you mentioned revenue
I have my thoughts here
I think there's very few if any crypto platforms
that generate revenue
that justifies most of the token valuations out there
and I'm curious if you feel otherwise
or if you think these things even trade
with any correlation to revenue
I'll answer that question with a question for you
out of the startups that you guys invest in
what percent of the startups you're investing in
are profitable at the time of investment
at the time of investment very few
a minority
a vast minority
I don't think investors are looking at these platforms
to necessarily be profitable
revenue generating is an indication
that people want to use your platform
it's not a bulletproof indication
it is possible to fake revenue numbers
for instance if you raise two billion dollars
and then you essentially
bleed that two billion dollars in the form of using your own platform
you could create two billion dollars of revenue
and then it will drop off the cliff
or you'll succeed
the reason people in crypto have been asking for revenue
is really two things
one is they've been asking for revenue in the form of buybacks
because they're desperate for net new buyers of this token
and it seems like nobody's buying them
and then the other reason is
they don't trust the teams
and they want to see the real numbers
so if you're a team and you go through all of this venture raise
and you raise 50 million dollars
and you aren't generating any revenue
then I think it's fair to say that
you probably don't have PMF
but let's say you're a team that goes through the metadata launchpad
and it's day one after the launchpad
you just got your first funding in
I think it's unreasonable to expect this team to be turning on
big revenue numbers after day one
but a lot of these teams are carrying valuations
well above 100 million dollars
well above 250 million dollars
I'd say if you look at the companies that we see
they're either doing a lot of revenue
and growing revenue really fast
on the traditional side
if they're carrying valuations of that sort
or they're profitable
and I don't think you said as much on the protocol side
there's still a gap there
this is where it gets a little sticky
because revenue begets revenue
so you're never going to make money
if you invest in a trend once it's already obvious
now tons of crypto valuations are inflated
but I think a lot of the valuations
are really a function of the expectation of future revenues
rather than the presence of current revenues
so it's the idea that does this company have a probability
of succeeding in capturing a market
and if it captures that market what is that market worth
and if that market's in five years or eight years
sure you can do your DCF and try to figure out
what it's going to be worth
but you don't know what the size of anything is in five or eight years
so your DCF is going to be just as good as the valuation
that the market is willing to buy and sell it at
and then to complicate this
you have simple supply and demand issues
so the supply of flow that is out there
for quality projects is so low
and the demand for these safe assets
is so high that you have premiums
and you have to pay a premium
and it's not like VCs are immune to paying premiums
when you see a really hot team go and raise capital
the VCs get priced out by other VCs as well
in a market like this it's really bizarre
we see one really good team that's not so high
raising at $12.5 million that has traction
has done a lot of the work
I see another team it's a good team just out of the gates
hasn't done anything yet raising at $30 million
and then I see another it's a great team
literally hasn't done anything yet raising at $50 million
so what you see in how these VCs are funding these things
is they're paying a huge premium for the talent
because the talent is the scarce thing
there's a prescribed probabilism to it
exactly and maybe we put our probabilities a little bit too high
that's the case crypto is an optimistic industry
recently it hasn't felt that way but generally speaking it is
a number goes up in our minds
so yeah we're going to weight our probabilities a little bit high
these things are going to be overpriced
if you look at the lending markets
I would love to sit here and tell you that I think
the lending markets are underpriced categorically
I think that they're underpriced but not categorically
and I think you have to have a five year investment horizon
for that to be the case
but if you put in a two or three year investment horizon
and do my model it will tell you that you're going to be overpaying
so the question is do you want to be overpaying now
or you want to be overpaying in the future
yeah I think the question we ask sometimes on this
which I don't have a great answer for to be fair
is if you combine the market caps
of all those $200 million protocols
the fictional ones that we were talking about
of the layer ones of the leading lending protocols
and you compile them into
the winning cohort in five years
which numbers more
because you would argue if Aave becomes big enough
it's a trillion dollar token or a hundred million dollar token
as long as that exceeds the total value
that everyone's paying for these things today
then you can justify that probabilism
I think wrapped into that
is hand waving over a lot of these ghost coins
that we all know is not worth the money it is
and probably the reason that these things are at this value
it's not like this is changing hands often
the reason that they're at this value is because
the holders either lost their coins
or they can't do anything with the money anyways
maybe it's dark money
so they just sit in these protocols
are you talking about the DeFi protocols
or you're talking about Bitcoin Cash and Hedera Hashgraph
yeah the NEOs, the Dino coins
if you look at any of the teams that are shipping in DeFi
and you look at the collective valuation of these
I think you would look at this valuation and be like
this is not even close to what the TAM is
if this thing succeeds
and then the question just becomes
how do you go from a
early stage protocol to monetization
and this is where we see a lot of the teams struggle
and this is why I pass on a lot of feels
is because the leaps that you have to take
to make this either more than what it is today
or to be able to actually charge your users more
without getting disintermediated
it's a stretch probabilistically
so the valuation is too high
did you see his seeps tweet the other day on Monad?
yeah the probability thinking for valuation
and just the justification that when you're paying
these sorts of premiums
you are justifying it
in the scope
of the winning outcome
of how large a thing this can be
and he believes that a lot of the pessimistic thinking
we're paying today is a loss of that
belief in the upside
I think he's incredibly right
the other day somebody asked me
they looked at me and they said
do you think Ethereum is really worth
300 billion dollars?
and this is a tough question to answer
because Ethereum there's nobody above it
when you look at smart contracts
so this is the ceiling
this is when a seed talks about
what's the probability that Monad becomes the next Ethereum
should the valuation be some percentage of that
what he's not asking is
what is Ethereum worth
he's just saying the market values are that this
consider the market to be completely sane
I think he's saying there's this much money in the market
which maybe we're saying the same thing
but I'm to some extent a believer that
a lot of these valuations applied
are just based on the supply of capital
and the supply of capital is saying that
whether it is Ethereum or something else
that's the amount of capital that's going to go into
the premium L1 or L1s
maybe I would ask you to share your thoughts
on stablecoins and how stablecoins
impact the valuation
of other altcoins
yeah
I think stablecoins tokenized assets
and memecoins frankly
a broader range of tokens
are materially detrimental to altcoins
from this liquidity perspective
I think that's de facto true
and this goes back to what I would argue is
somewhat basic rates theory
around the idea that equity markets struggle
during higher rates environments
and during lower rate environments
you see more speculation
I think that's purely because
of that liquidity struggle
I think it has to be
it's very easy to get pessimistic in crypto
and in an environment like this
it's a weird bear market because it feels like
the valuations are quite high
but it also feels like across the board
sentiment literally cannot be worse
within crypto
outside of crypto people are optimistic
exactly and the thing
that I always like to remind myself is
crypto sits so far out on the risk curve
that it is one macro trade
it is essentially one macro trade
this is why we don't like crypto hedge funds
who say that they're macro funds doing crypto
it's because just by being in crypto
you have taken a macro outlook
and you've made that bet
if you were a real macro fund you would be in tradfi
and then you would maybe bet on crypto sometimes
you wouldn't just be in crypto
so what happens to us is
obviously we get impacted by interest rates
probably the most out of any sector
because we're a risk asset
we're not just a risk asset
we're a risk asset that's extremely sensitive
to rates
so you have to recognize where we are
in the world of rates
it's no surprise that the last real
bull market COVID
with zero interest rates
and ever since then the US has just been
tightening and tightening and tightening its bell
and within the past couple months
we've started to see that change
I don't think there's a better bull case for crypto
period
I don't disagree with the irony of all this
crypto springs from the disillusionment
of people
maybe even call people the libertarian lean
of monetary policy
carried out by governments
the US government and thus
thrives when monetary policy
is arguably problematic
reckless so when the crypto people
get arguably what they would want
which is a more responsible
monetary policy
crypto underperforms
because of the fact that then you actually
have a more reasonable monetary policy
that lessens the supposed
value of crypto
crypto is essentially the short trader in the crew
shout out to Fawzi
he's only happy when everybody else is sad
because essentially crypto does great
when we're in
hyperinflationary environment and rates are zero
exactly
so that's what I mean by the whole industry
it's a macro trade
there's no way to be a macro fund in crypto
you only have one mechanism which is go long
and then you could go short theoretically
but it's just one implementation of one viewpoint
so maybe we can tie this back
I think this is also another interesting
bull case for lending
and it's a little counterintuitive
but you take it one step and it makes sense
the lending markets
on the surface as interest rates
lower in the US
the lending rates should go down
said it was paribas
that means that lending markets make
less money
but what you see happen when that occurs
is interest rates go down
the borrow cost on lending markets will go down
and the volume of borrow
should go up because all of a sudden strategies
that we see that were
not possible at certain rates
become much more durable
much more possible
so you start to see a volume uptick
that volume uptick can be
by the fact that you have this summer
the seasonality coming back
and you start to see swap fees go up
you start to see other indicators
that this market is recovering
and when that happens
your basis trade comes back
so all of a sudden your basis trade
the yield is going up because you have
a lot of people in crypto who are trading
purpose and exaggerating price movements
and your lending rates are going down
which means that the yield you can make
in this really vanilla strategy
a couple loops actually
looks really attractive on a global level
especially when you compare it to T-bills
which have fallen off a cliff
so I really think lending markets are interesting
because in the high interest rate
environment they benefit from high interest rates
in the low interest rate
environment they benefit from low interest rates
to me it has all
of the workings of a really strong business
we could talk a little bit about some of the pitfalls
I think we will see
and where the lending market is going
do you have thoughts on that?
I'm a wine